awmi.net 2018-07-07

# Privacy Policy - Andrew Wommack Ministries

**Introduction**  
This Privacy Policy applies to all information received by Andrew Wommack Ministries, Inc. (AWM), both online and offline, on any platform, including, but not limited to, our websites, web applications, web services, mobile applications, streaming media applications, and third-party services, as well as any electronic, written, or oral communications (collectively, “Platforms”).

**Donor Information**  
We will not sell, share, or trade the names or personal information of our donors with any other entity or send mailings to our donors in the name of other organizations.

**Acceptance of Terms**  
By utilizing the Platforms, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**The Information We Collect**  
AWM collects the following types of information—directly from you and indirectly through third-party service providers and advertising partners (collectively, “Partners”).

**1\. Personal Information**  
For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, personal information means any information or set of information that identifies or could be used by or on behalf of AWM to identify, a natural person. Personal information does not include information regarding corporate entities or information that is encoded, aggregated, or anonymized, or publicly available information that has not been combined with non-public personal information.

Examples of different purposes for which we may collect personal information include, but are not limited to, the following:

● The registration process for AWM website accounts, events, product orders, newsletters, memberships, and partner sign-ups  
● Donations made to AWM or its affiliates  
● Job applications submitted to AWM  
● Voluntary submissions to AWM requesting information about our products and services, signing up to receive information from us, or sending us an email

**2\. Non-Personal Information**  
In addition to personal information, we may collect additional information that does not personally identify you (i.e., “non-personal information”). Non-personal information may be collected as follows:

**a. From Your Activity.** This is information that we may automatically collect when you visit, access, or use the Platforms, including, but not limited to, your IP address, internet service provider, browser type and language, referring and exit pages and URLs, date and time, amount of time spent on particular pages, which sections or features of the Platforms you visit, number of links you click while on a Platform, search terms used, operating system, and technical information about your client computing device.

**b. From Cookies and JavaScript Code.** This is information that we automatically collect using technical methods, including, but not limited to, cookies, JavaScript code, pixel tags, and other locally stored objects. Cookies are small packets of data that a website stores on your computer’s hard drive so that your computer will “remember” information about your visit. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to enhance your experience with the Platforms and to allow us to collect non-personal information. If you wish to disable the use of cookies, you should take necessary steps within your web browser’s security settings to block all cookies from the Platforms. Please consult your web browser’s documentation for information on how to do this and how to delete persistent cookies. However, if you decide not to accept cookies from us, the Platforms may not function properly. We use JavaScript code to trigger a sequence of events that includes viewing a first-party cookie (or setting that cookie if it does not already exist) and to help us tailor and optimize your visit to the Platforms.

Note: AWM assumes no responsibility for responding to Do Not Track (DNT) web browser signals. Consult external website polices regarding their response to DNT signals.

**Web Analytics**  
AWM has entered into agreements with certain partners to deliver relevant, user-targeted, non-intrusive advertising to help promote AWM events and services. These partners do not have access to any personal information and only access to non-personal information. They have their own policies that should be reviewed in connection with your use of the Platforms. Partners include, but are not limited to, Google Analytics.

AWM uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help a website’s operator analyze how users use the site. The non-personal information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers located around the world. Google will use this information for evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators, and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by them. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your web browser; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Platforms. By using the Platforms, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set forth above.

Google Analytics collects information anonymously. It reports Platform usage trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of Google Analytics without affecting how you use the Platforms. For more information on opting out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites you use, visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881>. For more information on the Google Privacy Policy, visit <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. 

**The Information Collected by or Through Third-party Advertising Companies**  
We may share other information about your activity on the Platforms with third parties for tailoring, analyzing, managing, reporting, and optimizing the advertising you see on the Platforms and elsewhere. These third parties may use cookies, pixel tags (also called web beacons or clear gifs), or other technologies to collect other information for such purposes. Pixel tags enable us, and these third-party advertisers, to recognize a browser’s cookie when a user visits the site on which the pixel tag is located, in order to learn which advertisement brings a user to a given website.

**How We Use and Share the Information**  
We use personal and non-personal information to process your donations, solicit your feedback, inform you about our products, events, and services, communicate information and ministry updates to you, and process product orders.

We may also use or share personal information and other information as described below:

● We may employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples may include providing technical assistance and marketing services. These other companies will have access to personal and other information—only as necessary— to perform their functions and to the extent permitted by law.  
● In an ongoing effort to better understand visitors to the Platforms, we may analyze other information in aggregate form to operate, maintain, manage, and improve our company, products, and services. This aggregate information does not identify individuals personally. We may share this aggregate data with our affiliates, agents, and business partners. We may also disclose aggregated user statistics to describe our company, products, and services to current and prospective business partners and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.  
● We may share some or all personal information and other information with any of our parent companies, subsidiaries, or other companies under common control.  
● To the extent permitted by law, we may also disclose personal information and other information (a) when required by law, court order, or other government or law enforcement authority or regulatory agency, or (b) whenever we believe that disclosing such information is necessary or advisable (for example, to protect the rights, property, or safety of AWM or other affiliated entities).

**Accessing and Modifying Information and Communication Preferences**  
Upon request, AWM and/or Charis will grant individuals reasonable access to Personal Information that we hold about them. For example, visitors to the Platform who have provided Personal Information to us may review and/or make changes to the same by contacting AWM or Charis. In addition, individuals may manage their receipt of marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of any AWM or Charis marketing e-mail or by following the instructions found on the Platform. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to process such requests in a timely manner. You should be aware, however, that it is not always possible to completely remove or modify information in our subscription databases.

**Accessing and Modifying Information and Communication Preferences**  
Upon request, AWM will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that we hold about them. For example, users of the Platform, who have provided personal information to us, may review or make changes to the same by contacting AWM. In addition, individuals may manage their receipt of marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of any AWM marketing email or by following the instructions found on the Platform. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to process such requests in a timely manner. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, contact us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section below. You can also request to have your personal information removed based on applicable law.

**How We Protect the Information**  
We take commercially reasonable steps to protect personal information and other information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. We use encryption, where possible, to keep your data private while in transit. We cannot guarantee that the information that you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to and from us over the public internet. Email sent to or from the Platform may not be secure, and you should, therefore, take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email.

We review our methods of information collection, storage, and processing, including physical security measures, to prevent unauthorized access to our systems.

We restrict access to personal information to necessary employees or contractors who need the information for processing. Anyone with this access is subject to strict confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

**Important Notice to Non-U.S. Residents**  
It is important to note that the Platforms and their associated servers are located in the United States and other countries around the world. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that any personal and non-personal information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the Platforms and by providing us information in any manner, you consent to this transfer and our use of the information and data provided by you in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section below. We will investigate your question, respond to your inquiry, and attempt to resolve any concerns regarding your privacy question.

**External Websites**  
The Platform may contain links to third-party websites. AWM has no control over the privacy practices or content of those websites and is, therefore, not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of those websites. You should read and agree to the applicable Privacy Policy when visiting any other website.

**Children**  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not give us any personal information. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s internet usage and help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children to never provide personal information without parental permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases.

**California Residents**  
Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who have an established business relationship with AWM may choose to opt out of our sharing of your personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to (a) opt out or (b) request certain information regarding our disclosure of your personal information to third parties for direct marketing purposes, please contact us as described in the “How to Contact Us” section below.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date stated on this policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please refer to it on a regular basis. Be aware that, to the extent permitted by applicable law, our use of personal information and other information is governed by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time we collect the information.

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, would like a copy of the information held on you, or wish to request removal of personal information based on applicable law, please contact AWM via the following methods.

● email to [info@awmi.net](mailto:info@awmi.net) with “PRIVACY POLICY” in the subject line; or  
● postal mail to Privacy Administrator, Andrew Wommack Ministries, PO Box 3333, Colorado Springs, CO 80934-3333

Effective date: June 26, 2018
